Guide to the World War I Posters File [1914]-1920 PR 55-7
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Recruitment, 1
  - Subseries I.3: Navy, 3
    - Will you supply eyes for the Navy? Navy Ships need binoculars and spy glasses / Will you help us "stand watch" on a destroyer (Folder 5)
      A blindfolded sailor on board ship on stormy sea trying to "feel" his way rather than "seeing"
    - USN/This gun is "Over There"/Where are you?/Man the guns of the Navy, get in the game/Enlist, 1917 (Folder 5)
      gun
    - US Navy requires firemen/2nd class and 3rd class/For battleships, cruisers and transports../Pay Firemen 3rd class $36.20 per month board and clothing allowed Naval Recruiting Offices, 1044 Chapel St., New Haven/Waterbury/Hartford, Bridgeport, New London, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - The Naval Militia / The US Navy / The state of New York already has 28 divisions as follows:.. .. .. To increase its force from 2000 to 4500 new unites are being organized / Requirements / Enrollment blanks may be obtained at .. … (Folder 5)
    - Halt the hun / Submarine / Clear the road to France / Join the Navy, Naval Reserve, or Coast Guard / One service, one call (Folder 5)
      Men, women, children huddled on lifeboat, sailor pointing to rescue ship
    - Navy! Uncle Sam is calling you! Enlist in the Navy! Do it now! I want you!, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - What the Navy is doing / Converted yacht makes huns surrender.. .. .. Once a pleasure yacht, the Venetia became a patrol ship in the Navy (Folder 5)
      3 photos: The Venetia patrol ship, gunner EL Jacobs who dropped the depth bomb which crippled the U39, sailors hoisting star on smokestack
    - What the Navy is doing / The second anniversary of the Navy's arrival in Europe, 1917-05-14 (Folder 5)
      Admiral Sims being welcomed by Asst. Sec. Roosevelt in the Office f the Seey of the Navy; painting in rear shows arrival of US destroyers in Queensland, Ireland; photo of Capt Taussig, commander
    - The first line of defense needs you enlist in the navy (Folder 5)
      Black destroyer at sea
    - When you fire remember this / Enlist in the navy', 1918 (Folder 5)
      Children on Lusitania life boat being rescued by sailors
    - Torpedo Boat destoyers passing in review, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - Keep the American flag on the seas / Jinn the navy / Enlist now your country needs you (Folder 5)
      Battleships on hight seas
    - What the Navy is doing / Road to France the Navy keeps it open / Enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
      9 photos of different duties (lookouts, airplane patrol, convoying, mass ship scenes, manning guns, eating meals)
    - U S ee the world! / ave your money! / erve the world! / Navy / Information gladly given at US Navy Recruiting Stations (Folder 5)
      Sailor pointing to the sign
    - I'm doing my duty / Are you? / Your navy needs you this minute (Folder 5)
      Sailor with bayonet
    - U.S. Navy / It is hereby directed that the authorized enlisted strength of the navy be increased to 87,000 men Woodrow Wilson / Make this a new leaf; trun it over and see what you ought to do, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - First call / I need you in the Navy this minute / Our country will always be proudest of those who answered the first call / Navy Recruiting Stations: 34 East 23 St / 115 Flatbush Ave, Brooklyn, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - For liberty's sake / Enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
    - U.S. navy requires firemen / 2nd class and 3rd class / For battleships, cruisers, and transports .. .. .. / Pay firemen 3rd class, $36.20 per month, board an clothing allowed Naval Recruiting Offices, 1044 Chapel St, New Haven, Waterbury, Hartford..., 1917 (Folder 5)
    - USN / This gun is "over there" / Where are you? / Man the guns of the Navy / Get in the game, 1917 (Folder 5)
    - The Navy strikes now / Follow the flag for freedom / Your choice, Natural Reserve, Coast Guard, or Navy / 394 E. 150th St. (Folder 5)
      "Liberty" leading navy
    - The Naval militia /The US Navy/The state of New York/Already has 28 divisions as follows:... to increase its... force from 2000 to 4500 new units are being organized/Requirements/Enrollment blanks may be obtained at (Folder 5)
    - Your Country Calls/Join the Navy/For Information/Apply Recruiting Station or Navy League (Folder 5)
    - U.S. Navy needs Americans to man the battle fleet / Enlist at 962 Chapel St., 1917 (Folder 5)
    - Protect your flag/Navy needs you/Apply recruitment station or Navy League, 1917 (Folder 5)
      Flags of Britain, U.S., France/Sailor with HMS hat & sailor with 'France' on hat
    - What the Navy is doing / Heroes of the deep / Enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
      Photo of men of the Armed Guard
    - What the Navy is doing/Heroes of the deep/Enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
      photo of men of the Armed Guard
    - Will you supply eyes for the Navy? Navy ships need binoculars and spyglasses/Will you help us "stand watch" on a destroyer (Folder 5)
    - Life in the Navy/Food for fighters/Come in for fighting and big eats and enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
      6 photos of food gathering, cooked on plates, sailors eating
    - What the Navy is doing/The road to France The Navy keeps it open/Enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
      9 photos of different duties (lookouts, airplane patrol, convoying, on board ship mass scenes/manning guns, eating meals)
    - What the Navy is doing/Converted Yacht Makes Huns Surrender..Once a Pleasure Yacht, the Venetia became a Patrol Ship in the Navy (Folder 5)
      3 photos:The Venetia Patrol Ship/Gunner E.L. Jocobus who dropped the depth bomb which crippled the U-39/Sailors hoisting star on smokestack.
    - The first line of defense needs you enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
    - When you fire remember this/Enlist in the Navy, 1918 (Folder 5)
      children on Lusitania Life Boat being rescued by sailors
    - I'm doing my duty/Are you?/Navy needs you this minute (Folder 5)
    - Your country calls / Join the Navy / For information /Apply Recruiting Station or Navy League (Folder 5)
    - Life in the Navy / Food for fighters / Come in for fighting and big eats and enlist in the Navy (Folder 5)
    - What the Navy is doing/The second anniversary of the Navy's arrival in Europe, 1917-05-14 (Folder 5)
      Photo: Admiral Sims being welcomed by Asst. Secy Roosevelt in the Office of the Secy of the Navy. Painting in rear shows arrival of US destroyers in Queensland, Ireland/photo of Capt. Tausip...
    - Your country needs you Join the Navy, 1916 (Folder 6)
      Saluting sailor/Statue of Liberty
    - Your country needs you / Join the Navy / Don't wait for the next man to make up his mind / Join now, 1916 (Folder 6)
      see notes
    - Your country needs you Join the Navy, 1916 (Folder 6)
      Saluting sailor, Statue of Liberty
    - Remember the Lusitania / Kipling quote.. .. .. / "The Hun is at the gate" / Men wanted / US Navy (Folder 6)
      Sailor carrying dead children
    - Yale Naval Training Unit / Report to 117 Wall Street / At once (Folder 6)
    - Are you with me fellows? Altogether!! (Folder 6)
    - Which is most important??? The man behind the machine or the man behind the gun? (Folder 6)
    - A signal from the U.S. Navy/To healthy Americans age 1730/See the world, save your money, serve your country (Folder 6)
      Sailor with semaphore
    - "Wake up America!" / A glimpse of the "Wake Up America Day" parade in NYC this window has been donated .. .. .. As a Naval Recruiting Station, 1917-04-19 (Folder 6)
      Wake Up America Day parade
    - Yale Naval training unit/Report to 117 Wall Street/At once (Folder 6)
    - Your country needs you/Join the Navy/Don't wait for the next man to make up his mind/Join now!, 1916 (Folder 6)
    - Remember the Lusitania/Kipling quote "... The Hun is at the gate."/Men wanted/U.S. Navy (Folder 6)
      Sailor carrying dead child
    - Hospital Corps US Navy (Folder 6)
    - A wonderful opportunity for you/United States Navy (Folder 6)
      sailor with luggage
    - Hospital corps/U.S. Navy (Folder 6)
    - United States Navy (Folder 6)
      2 sailors, 1 with harpoon, 1 with flag
    - Only the Navy can stop this (Folder 6)
      german soldier with bloody sword and drowned babies
    - Your country needs you!/Join the Navy now! (Folder 6)
      sailor with bugle
    - Wake up New Yorkers/Your country needs you to make the world safe/Enlist today/Apply 34 E. 23 St., N.Y./115 Flatbush Ave., Brooklyn (Folder 6)
    - Come on you seacooks/Enlist in the Naval Reserve/For the war only, 1918 circa (Folder 6)
      Sailor chef
    - Your country is at war / You must help if you are a red blooded man between 18 and 35 years of age through the navy, 1917 (Folder 6)
      2 battleships
    - Your country needs you in the U.S. Navy/Enlist now/Recruiting stations 34 East 23 St., NY City/115 Flatbush Ave. B'klyn (Folder 6)
    - Follow the boys in blue / For home and country / Enlist in the navy / 394 E 150 St (address handwritten) (Folder 6)
      Lining up for the battleship
    - War clouds gather!/"Manhood willing but unarmed"/Help the Navy/Join the Navy League (Folder 6)
    - He is getting our country's signal / Are you? / Join the navy (Folder 6)
    - Your country needs you inn the US Navy / Enlist now / Recruiting Stations 34 East 23 St, NYC, 115 Flatbush Ave, B'klyn (Folder 6)
    - Only the Navy can stop this (Folder 6)
      German soldier with skull and crossbones on helmet and waistcoat holding bloody sapbre and dagger standing on drowned babies
    - Your country needs you! / Join the Navy now! (Folder 6)
      Sailor with bugle
    - Wake up New Yorkers / Your country needs youto make the world safe / Enlist today / apply 34 East 23 ST NY / 115 Flatbush Ave B'klyn (Folder 6)
    - War clouds gather! / Manhood willing but unarmed / Help the Navy / Join the Navy League (Folder 6)
    - A wonderful opportunity for you / United States Navy (Folder 6)
      Sailor with luggage
    - Are you with me fellows? Altogether!!! (Folder 6)
    - Your country is at war/You must help if you are a red blooded man between 18 and 35 years of age through the Navy, 1917 (Folder 6)
    - Extra/Your country needs you in the U.S. Navy at once (Folder 6)
    - Come on you seacooks / Enlist in the naval reserve / For the war only, 1918 (?) (Folder 6)
    - A signal from the U.S. Navy / To healthy Americans / Age 17 30 / See the world, save your money, serve your country (Folder 6)
      Sailor and semaphore
    - Which is most important??? / The man behind the machine or the man behind the gun? (Folder 6)
    - Extra / Your country needs you in the US Navy at once (Folder 6)
    - He is getting our country's signal/Are you?/Join the Navy (Folder 6)
      sailor with semaphore
    - United States Navy (Folder 6)
      2 sailors, 1 with harpoon, 2 with flag
    - Follow the boys in blue / For home and country / Enlist in the Navy/(handwritten: 394 E. 150 St.) (Folder 6)
      lining up for the battleship
    - "Wake up America!"/A glimpse of the "Wake up America Day" parade in NYC The window has been donated... As a Naval Recruiting Station, 1917-04-19 (Folder 6)
      Wake Up America Day Parade
  - Subseries I.4: Selective Service Draft Board / Ephemera, 4
    - [Selective service draft notice; in Chinese?], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - A Petition / to the Congress of the United States for the enactment of an Universal Service Law... (Folder 7)
      Petition is bordered by Red white and blue border looking like a ribbon or banner.
    - [Selective service draft notice in Greek], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Navesti pro registranty / Oznamte mistnimu sboru kazdou zmenu adresy po registro vani... [Selective service draft notice, in Czech?], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Help! / Our Country Calls / Help! / This Is the Way / A Liberty Bond! / Our country is at war …, ca. 1917 (Folder 7)
      Cartoon of Uncle Sam handing liberty bonds to a crowd; reverse bears three flags and the statue of liberty
    - Avviso al registranti / Se dopo la registrazione cambiate casa, informatene subito il vostro local board... [Selective service draft notice in Italian] (Folder 7)
    - For the starving children of armenia / American Consul cables for immediate aid, 1917-04-14 (Folder 7)
      A picture of poverty in Armenia / portrait of five people standing in a line
    - [Selective service draft notice in Hebrew or Yiddish], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Governor's Message for State of Connecticut to our boys in France / Back up these boys of ours! / Show you're proud of them! / Save and sacrifice for victory! / Taking advantage... (Folder 7)
    - This is to ceritfy that the Branch No. 2 WarSavings Society Muser Brothers of New York, N.Y. is affiliated with the War Loan Organization, Savings Division, United States Treasury Department..., 1919-06-02 (Folder 7)
      Benjamin Franklin, smiling at center
    - Selective Service (Draft) / Notice / Persons residing on this block (Both Sides This Side only Strike out) are within the jurisdiction of Local Board No. / They must register at..., 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Selective Service (Draft) / Notice / Persons residing on this block (Both Sides This Side only Strike out) are within the jurisdiction of Local Board No. / They must register at..., 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - [Selective service draft notice in Turkish], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Ring me again / Third Liberty Loan / Buy U.S. Government Bonds / Push over door knob (Folder 7)
      blue image of bell, circle above [bell-shaped sign]
    - Your child is safe / While 400,000 Armenian Syrian Greek Persian orphans are starving, 1919-01-12 (Folder 7)
    - Shooting on this property is prohibited / War / Protect the birds as a war measure! / The food destroyed in America…, ca. 1917 (Folder 7)
    - The greatest mother in the world / Red Cross Christmas Roll Call Dec. 1623rd (Folder 7)
      Nurse or mother holding small soldier in arms with red cross
    - Regisztralok Figyelmebe! / Ha regisztralas utan lakascimet valtoztat ertesitse arrol a helyi sorozo hatosagot, Local Boardot.. .[selective service draft notice in Hungarian?], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Avis Aux Conscrits / En cas de changement d'adresse apres vous etre fait enregistrer, informezen le bureau... [Selective service draft notice in French], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
    - Starving / Help now / Millions are starving in bible lands Armenia Syria Cucasus Egypt Persia Palestine / Ten cents per day will … (Folder 7)
      Woman on knees, reaching up, with child beside her lying on the ground
    - "Is it nothing to you, all ye that pass by?" / Lamenations of Jeremiah, 1918 (Folder 7)
      Two women and a man mourning over dead child
    - Wear your button / It is an evidence of your loyalty., 1919 (Folder 7)
      Red Cross button, with 1919
    - Young Men of Twentyone. / The President and the Congress of the United States require that you register with your local draft board on Wednesday, June 5, 1918..., 1918-06 (Folder 7)
    - [Selective service draft notice in foreign language Russian?], 1918-09-12 (Folder 7)
  - Subseries I.5: Tanks Corps, 5
    - Treat 'em rough / Join the tanks / United States Tank Corps / See Recruiting Officer at Adolphus Hotel (Folder 8)
      Flying, enraged colourful tomcat
    - Join the Tanks/(long printed message) (Folder 8)
      outline of soldier's torso (cap off page) - long printed message
    - Wanted: husky young Americans/Apply at room 516 Consumers Building/It's a dare!/Join the Tanks (Folder 8)
      Soldier waving/tanks in background
    - Treat 'em rough/Join the Tanks/United States Tank Corps/Open to all classes 18 to 45/See recruiting officer at tenth floor, 19 W. 44th Street (Folder 8)
      Flying, enraged tomcat
    - Treat 'em rough/Join the Tanks/United States Tank Corps/See recruiting officer at Adolphus Hotel (Folder 8)
      Attacking tomcat
    - Join the Black Toms (The Tanks) / They treat 'em rough (Folder 8)
      Flying black tom cat
    - Join the tanks / (long printed message) (Folder 8)
      Outline of soldier's torso
    - Treat 'em rough / Join the tanks / United States Tank Corps / Open to all classes 18 to 45 / See Recruiting Officer at tenth floor, 19 W. 44th Street (Folder 8)
    - Join the Black Toms (the tanks)/They treat 'em rough (Folder 8)
      Flying black Tom cat
    - Wanted: Husky young Americans / Apply at room 516 Consumers Building / It's a dare! / Join the tanks (Folder 8)
      Soldier waving; tanks in background
    - Join the tanks / See service soon / Treat 'em rough (Folder 8)
      Tomcat with US helmet on tank
    - Join the tanks/See service soon/Treat 'em rough (Folder 8)
      Tomcat with U.S. helmet on tank
  - Subseries I.6: American Field Service, 6
    - American Field Service (Folder 9)
    - Can you drive a car? Will you drive one in France? / American Field Service (Folder 9)
      "Liberty" protecting wounded
    - Can you drive a car? Will you drive one in France?/ American Field Service (Folder 9)
    - You drive a car here Why not a transport in France?/American Field Service, 1917 (Folder 9)
      transport car
    - American Field Service (Folder 9)
    - You drive a car here why not transport in France? / American Field Service, copyright 1917 (Folder 9)
      Transport car
  - Subseries I.7: Non New-York Local and State Regiments and National Guard, 7
    - "Go Getter" Pershing/He wants your help/Join the National Guard, 1917 (Folder 10)
      ill. of Pershing
    - Our hat's in the ring/Come and put one on/Join the National Guard (Folder 10)
      Hat
    - "Gogetter" Pershing / He wants your help / Join the National Guard, 1917 (Folder 10)
      lllustration of Pershing
    - Are you trained to defend your country? Plattsburg (Folder 10)
      soldiers with rifles
    - Uphold the tradition of Indiana (Folder 10)
      soldier on horseback/artillery
    - The Second Artillery/18401917/Needs 200 real men will you be one? (Folder 10)
    - Come on boys! Give the Guard a fighting chance (Folder 10)
      marchign soldiers
    - 2285 New Yorkers volunteered in one week/Is your name on the list?, 1917 (Folder 10)
    - Some backing/The Empire state seeds soldiers/Join the New York State Guard (Folder 10)
      Uncle Sam, Father Knickerbocker, Young Soldier
    - Send off day/To the New York National Guard (Folder 10)
      soldier waving goodbye to crowd led by Uncle Sam
    - Somewhere in France doing his share/Join the National Guard, 1917 (Folder 10)
      Soldier with bayonet
    - The minute men of today are going to Plattsburg (Folder 10)
      minutemen and soldier
    - Are you trained to do your share? Plattsburg (Folder 10)
      marching soldiers
    - Hold the fort for I am coming!, 1917 (Folder 10)
    - Our hat's in the ring / Come and put one on / Join the National Guard (Folder 10)
    - Somewhere in France doing his share / Join the National Guard, 1917 (Folder 10)
    - Uphold the tradition of Indiana (Folder 10)
      Soldiers on horseback; artillery
    - Come on boys! Give the guard a fighting chance (Folder 10)
      Marching soldiers
    - The Second Artillery / 1840 1917 / Needs 200 real men / Will you be one? (Folder 10)
    - Hold the fort for I am coming!, c 1917 (Folder 10)
- Series II: Monetary Appeals, 2
  Series II: Monetary Appeals, includes posters produced to encourage Americans to buy the first four Liberty Loans, and the Victory (Fifth) Liberty Loan, as well as other miscellaneous war bonds and war savings stamps. Some of the most recognizeable posters of the era, such as Joseph Pennell's "That Liberty Shall Not Perish From The Earth... " are housed here.
  - Subseries II.1: First Liberty Loan, 8
    - You/Buy a Liberty Bond/Lest I perish, 1917 (Folder 11)
      Statue of Liberty pointing at you (almost a spoof of similar image by Macauley in file)
    - You/Buy A Liberty Bond/ Lest I perish/Get behind the government/Liberty Loan of 1917 (Folder 11)
      Statue of Liberty pointing at you
    - Have you bought your Bond?/Liberty Loan, 1917 (Folder 11)
  - Subseries II.2: Second Liberty Loan, 9
    - Our daddy is fighting at the front for you Back him up Buy a US Government bond of the 2nd liberty loan of 1917 (Folder 12)
      brother and sister with flag
    - "Shall we be more tender with our dollars than with the lives of our sons" Buy a United States Gov't Bond of the 2nd Liberty Loan of 1917" (Folder 12)
      Uncle Sam/Statue of Liberty/Soldiers on Parade
    - Remember your first thrill of American liberty/Your duty buy United States Government bonds/2nd Liberty Loan of 1917 (Folder 12)
      immigrants on ship sailing past Statue of Liberty
    - Ring it again/Buy a US Government bond of the/Second Liberty Loan of 1917/Help your country and yourself (Folder 12)
      Liberty Bell
    - "The time has come to conquer or submit" "For us there is but one choice. We have made it" President Wilson/Buy a bond of the 2nd Liberty Loan and help win the war, 1917 (Folder 12)
      portrait bust of President Wilson flanked by US flags
    - Women! Help America's sons win the war/Buy U.S. Government bonds/2nd Liberty Loan of 1917 (Folder 12)
      elderly woman reaching out for help (ie a female Uncle Sam) - war scene in background
    - Second Liberty Loan of 1917/Buy a bond (Folder 12)
      US Treasury, Washington, DC (cardboard)
    - "Shall we be more tender with our dollars than with the lives of our sons"/McMeadoo(?), Secretary of the Treasury/Second Liberty Loan, 1917 (Folder 12)
      soldier, sailor, carrying US flag
    - I own a Liberty Bond/Wear a US Government Bond holder's button/It is a badge of honor, 1917 (Folder 12)
      button with Statue of Liberty and slogan - cardboard
    - The Hun his mark/Blot it out/With/Liberty Bonds (Folder 12)
      bloody hand print
    - Feelings of the man who delays buying his Liberty Bonds, 1917 (Folder 12)
      cartoon strip
    - Buy a Liberty Bond of the US Government/And wear this button It is a badge of honor, 1917 (Folder 12)
      Statue of Liberty on button printed "I own a Liberty Bond".
    - Before sunset/Buy a US Government bond/Of the/2nd Liberty Loan of 1917 (Folder 12)
  - Subseries II.3: Third Liberty Loan, 10
    - Are you 100% American?/Prove IT!/Buy US Government bonds/Third loan/U.S. Treasury will pay interest every six months, 1918 (Folder 13)
      Amreican Eagle flanked by guns
    - Will you be ready tomorrow to make munitions for Germany? If not, invest in Liberty Bonds today, 1917 (Folder 13)
      Hun and other soldiers arresting man at gunpoint
    - Halt the Hun/Buy U.S. Government bonds/Third Liberty Loan (Folder 13)
      soldier blocking Hun from attacking woman and child
    - Over the Top for You/Buy U.S. Government Bonds/Third Liberty Loan (Folder 13)
      soldier marching forward carrying and enveloped by US flag
    - My daddy bought me a Government bond/of the Third Liberty Loan/Did yours? (Folder 13)
      child hugging Liberty Loan
    - "Good bye, Dad, I'm off to fight for Old Glory, you buy U.S. Government bonds"/Third Liberty Loan (Folder 13)
      Soldier shaking hands with father before farmland in background
    - Ring it again / Buy US Government bonds/Third Liberty Loan (Folder 13)
      townspeople on square before Liberty Bell in Philadelphia
    - Remember! The flag of liberty/Support it/Buy U.S. Government bonds/3rd Liberty Loan (Folder 13)
      immigrants landing /US flag rear
    - Buy Liberty Bonds/"That government of the people, by the people, for the people shall not perish from the earth"/A. Lincoln (Folder 13)
      profile of Lincoln
    - Help New York/Win the right to fly/This flag by helping the/Rainbow Division/Third Liberty Loan honor roll (Folder 13)
      flag of Rainbow Division
    - After a zepplin raid in London/"But mother had done nothing wrong, had she daddy?"/Prevent this in New York/Invest in Liberty bonds, 1917 (Folder 13)